AMRITESH MISHRA

SKILLS

Data

Pipelines · ETL Pipelines · MySQL ·

Talend Open Studio • Spark • Talend •

MongoDB · Oracle · ELK · Jython ·

Erwin Data Intelligence Suite · Pyspark ·

AWS Athena · AWS S3

Programming

Python \cdot Java Core \cdot Shell Scripting \cdot

Jython

Cloud

AWS

STRENGTHS

Communication Skills

Able to boil down complex subjects to juniors. Patient, understanding, willing to help, is how my colleagues describe me.

Creativity

I put all my creative effort into finding a solution.

Result-oriented

I always make sure my team is on the right path.

Senior Data Engineer

SUMMARY

As I have started my carrier, I am ready to accept challenges and learn new things. I will not take a step back if I come across something new to learn.

Data Engineer with 6+ years of experience in building data intensive applications, tackling challenging architectural and scalability problems, collecting and sorting data in the healthcare field. Currently, working with ATOS Syntel and helping them migrate their salesforce and create APIs.

EDUCATION

B.Tech Information Technology

07/2013 - 07/2017

KIIT UNIVERSITY

Bhubaneshwar, OD

GPA **7.64** / 10.0

EXPERIENCE

Consultant

12/2021 - Present

Atos Syntel

Bengaluru,KA

Currently working here as a consultant here and developed some API to fetch different records for salesforce application and processed it further meanwhile working on CICD pipeline as well side by side for our code which we use to develop using Talend(ETL tool for data processing) and we used Databricks to store, clean, share and send those data for analysis to other team. AWS is our deployment method for our Talend and Python code.

- Worked in API creatoin to Connect to Salesforce using talend from different applications.
- Created pipelines for a shopping website where the data was in S3. They had to use the data and display it in AWS Athena using Python code.
- Using Python, ETL pipelines can be used to automate the creation of assets and attributes in salesforce.
- · Currently working on the migration of the database.

Software Engineer

11/2020 - 12/2021

erwin

Hyderabad, TE

Worked as an ETL developer here used different technologies like Jython, Python, Talend and Java. We have used their own product, which is a data governance platform tool called the data intelligence suite, which we designed according to customer requirements.

- Create differnt kind of connector for our client to use the Data intelligence suite to create mappings.
- Automated Data Stage tool for creating of mapping using Python
- · Worked with different clients Google, Walmart Etc.

Solution Integrator

09/2017 - 11/2020

Ericsson

Bengaluru, KA

Worked on 11 Projects in Ericsson and worked in different skills which included Python, ETL(Talend), Shell Scripting, ELK and have used agile methodologies in all the projects worked .Went onsite from this company for one of the project to UK for Client Demo to show the POC for ELK using python.

- Automated ETL processes, making it easier to wrangle data and reducing time by as much
- Increased the efficiency of the data fetching by approximately 30% using query optimization and indexing
- Implemented ELK solution.